# 你看 我們廠裡的這個橘子啊 快熟啦
Look! The tangerines at our site, are almost ready.
# 摘個來吃一下
Let me get one and have a try.
# 這個是砂糖桔哦
This is "sugar tangerine" (very sweet tangerine).
# 很新鮮的
It's really fresh.
# 誒呼
Ehu~!
# 想跑
You wanna run away?
# 這個到手的東西竟然想跑
Nothing can run away from my hands.
# 哇 這個
Wa! This is...
# 嗯
Um!
# 有點酸酸甜甜的
It's like sweet and sour.
# 還可以呦
Not bad.
# 小狗
Doggy
# 小狗上去抓鳥去了
The doggy went preying for birds up there.
# 今年長了很少
There are just a few this year.
# 可能一百個都不到
I think we don't even have a hundred.
# 這裡面還有一點
There are a few more here inside.
# 我們去看一下小豬
Let's have a look at the piglets.
# 小豬 豬媽媽 豬媽媽在餵奶了
The piglets, the mother, the mother is nursing them.
# 在那裡
Over there
# 你看這條公豬
Look at this boar!
# 又看著我 你是不是又想拱我
It's looking at me again? You wanna attack me again, don't you?
# 那公豬又想看 又看 一直盯著我
Again the boar wants to look, look again, it keeps staring at me.
# 我拿個棍子
I take a stick with me,
# 防一下身
to defend myself.
# 不然它真的要拱我了
It would really attack me otherwise.
# 誒呀 小狗崽那麼大啦
Aya! The little piglets are already that big!
# 兩天
Two days,
# 兩天就那麼大了啦
they've grown so much in just two days.
# 小豬
Piglets!
# 一二三四五六七八九十
One, two, three, four, five, six, seven, eight, nine, ten
# 只有十條啊
So just ten.
# 借你小豬崽給我玩一下行下行
May I borrow your piglets and play for a while?
# 行下行
May I?
# 行還是不行
Yes or no?
# 行是不是 我過來啦
Did you say yes? Alright! I'm coming.
# 我手上有棍子 別咬我哦
I have a stick in my hand. Don't bite me!
# 小朋友 過來 過來玩一下
Hey kids! Come here! Let's play together!
# 誒呦 誒呦 搞不得 搞得不
Ayu! Ayu! No, no, no, no, no....
# 還是算了吧
Forget it!
# 那條公豬
The boar,
# 公豬來啦
the boar is coming.
# 那條 公豬來啦 算啦算啦
The, the boar is coming. Aya! Forget it, forget it.
# 這條小公豬是不是想偷奶喝
Is this little boar trying to steal the milk?
# 把它趕走
Let me drive it out.
# 你們三個人在這裡玩就好了
All three of you just play here!
# 這條 這條母豬好胖啊
This sow, this sow is really fat.
# 天天都給它吃好多
It has a lot to eat everyday.
# 每天都給它吃一大桶
I give it a huge bucket,
# 一大 一大桶那個飯
a huge, a huge bucket of, of rice everyday,
# 飯跟那個米糠
rice with bran.
# 現在都好胖啊
So it's now really fat.
# 現在天氣那麼冷 它都不筧得冷
It doesn't feel cold at all, even it's so cold these days.
# 你給小它那麼多稻草 它就在這裡
You give it so much straw. So it's just staying here.
# 小豬崽看上去很健康哦
The piglets look very healthy.
# 那個最肥的小豬 在那裡
The fattest piggy, is over there.
# 它好像看到我們都怕啦
It seems to have phobia of us.
# 去看一下
Let's take a look.
# 小豬
Piggy!
# 我今天我不抓你
I'm not coming to catch you today.
# 看一下你
I just wanna see you.
# 前面那兩條豬 你看
The other two pigs, look,
# 它
they,
# 喝了酒糟
they've taken the distiller grains.
# 醉著醉著
While being drunk,
# 都已經下了鍋
they've been sent to the pot.
# 你看 我都沒把你下了鍋
Look! But I didn't send you to the pot.
# 對你多好啊
I'm always treating you well.
# 要聽話
Be a good piggy!
# 出外面去玩多好
It's so much fun out there.
# 你就是 就是不聽話
But you are, you're just naughty.
# 它生氣了
It's angry.
# 這兩條小母豬好像懷孕了 肚子那麼大
These two little sows seem to be pregnant. Their bellies are that large.
# 那麼小
They're still that small,
# 肚子就那麼大
but the bellies are already that large.
# 好啦 今天的視頻就到這裡啦
Alright! The video ends here.
# 我不要去嚇這些小豬了
I'd better not scare the piglets anymore.
# 看到我都怕
They're so scared of me.